<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming-language on Ankush Chadda</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/tags/programming-language/</link><description>Recent content in programming-language on Ankush Chadda</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 22:56:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankushchadda.in/tags/programming-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Javascript</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/introduction-to-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 22:56:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/introduction-to-javascript/</guid><description>Data Types Javascript has 6 primitive data types
number string boolean undefined null Symbol Objects Objects can store a collection of data types, which are then called properties. Each property has a key and value key is of string data types value can be of any data type. If a value is a functon, its called as a method Equality in Objects == or === only tests if both operands are same objects.</description></item><item><title>Scala Data Types</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/scala-data-types/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 19:07:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/scala-data-types/</guid><description>Scala&amp;rsquo;s unified type system Any is the super type Defines methods like - equals, hashCode, toString AnyVal represents value types. Double Float Long Int Short Byte Char Unit - Only one instance can be there - () Boolean AnyRef represent refernce types like List Nothing is subclass for all value types. Null is subclass for all reference types. Should not be used in Scala code.</description></item><item><title>Scala Introduction - The Basics</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/scala-introduction-the-basics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 11:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/scala-introduction-the-basics/</guid><description>Significant points of Scala Developed by Martin Odersky in 2004.  Is MultiParadigm - a blend of Functional and Object Oriented Paradigms Is statically typed Heavily uses Java libraries Encourages use of immutable data structures Basics Expressions are computable statements. For example 1+1
Values are names for results for expressions. Example val x = 1 + 1
These are immutable Variables are mutable names for expression results.</description></item></channel></rss>