<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Ankush Chadda</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Ankush Chadda</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 22:56:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankushchadda.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Javascript</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/introduction-to-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 22:56:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/introduction-to-javascript/</guid><description>Data Types Javascript has 6 primitive data types
number string boolean undefined null Symbol Objects Objects can store a collection of data types, which are then called properties. Each property has a key and value key is of string data types value can be of any data type. If a value is a functon, its called as a method Equality in Objects == or === only tests if both operands are same objects.</description></item><item><title>Scala Data Types</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/scala-data-types/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 19:07:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/scala-data-types/</guid><description>Scala&amp;rsquo;s unified type system Any is the super type Defines methods like - equals, hashCode, toString AnyVal represents value types. Double Float Long Int Short Byte Char Unit - Only one instance can be there - () Boolean AnyRef represent refernce types like List Nothing is subclass for all value types. Null is subclass for all reference types. Should not be used in Scala code.</description></item><item><title>Scala Introduction - The Basics</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/scala-introduction-the-basics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 11:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/scala-introduction-the-basics/</guid><description>Significant points of Scala Developed by Martin Odersky in 2004.  Is MultiParadigm - a blend of Functional and Object Oriented Paradigms Is statically typed Heavily uses Java libraries Encourages use of immutable data structures Basics Expressions are computable statements. For example 1+1
Values are names for results for expressions. Example val x = 1 + 1
These are immutable Variables are mutable names for expression results.</description></item><item><title>Building Unity Games</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/building-unity-games/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:51:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/building-unity-games/</guid><description>Learning to build unity games using different resources online like Oreilly.
This is my first game - Click here</description></item><item><title>Video Editing and Animation</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/video-editing-and-animation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 23:02:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/video-editing-and-animation/</guid><description>Animations Animations have always amazed me. Beautiful still images are brought to life, objects are set in motion, etc, all mainly depending how the animators imagined and implemented it, probably using a animation tool.
While my wife was making illustrations (portfolio), I decided to try my hands on some animations using Adobe After Effects. You can check it out here
Video Editing While this was fun, I also wanted to work on my Video Editing skills.</description></item><item><title>Postgres Indexes, PL/pgSQL and other learnings</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/postgres-indexes-and-other-learnings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 01:30:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/postgres-indexes-and-other-learnings/</guid><description>Recently I had to do a bit of reading on building Indexes in Postgres. Intrestingly I found some striking features about indexing types in Postgres
Extensions Postgres has a collection of extensions/modules. These are basically set of functions. One such module is pg_trgm. Quoting from the documentation- &amp;ldquo;pg_trgm provides functions and operators for determining the similarity of ASCII alphanumeric text based on trigram matching, as well as index operator classes that support fast searching for similar strings&amp;rdquo; Documentation</description></item></channel></rss>