<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>javascript on Ankush Chadda</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/tags/javascript/</link><description>Recent content in javascript on Ankush Chadda</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 22:14:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankushchadda.in/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Es6 Javascript</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/es6-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 22:14:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/es6-javascript/</guid><description>Iterables and Looping For looping over iterables, ES6 provides us with for of loop For looping over an object, Use Object.keys or .values in for of loop. Also, can use a for in loop where it iterates of enumarable properties. It will however iterate on keys not value of objects. Symbols New primitive added in ES6 Always unique Useful for keys with same names but different values Not enumarable Classes Just a wrapper around prototype inheritence.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Javascript 2</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/introduction-to-javascript-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 21:46:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/introduction-to-javascript-2/</guid><description>Understanding Scope The scope of a variable controls where it can be accessed from in the program. It can be of
Global Scope Function scope Block scope ( if / for etc ) Variable defination Variables can be defined with var, const and let keywords.
var keyword is function scoped let and const keyword are block scoped. this keyword Different from how other languages use this.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Javascript</title><link>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/introduction-to-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 22:56:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ankushchadda.in/posts/introduction-to-javascript/</guid><description>Data Types Javascript has 6 primitive data types
number string boolean undefined null Symbol Objects Objects can store a collection of data types, which are then called properties. Each property has a key and value key is of string data types value can be of any data type. If a value is a functon, its called as a method Equality in Objects == or === only tests if both operands are same objects.</description></item></channel></rss>